Calvin Chun-Yu Chan

Senior Software Engineer

hello@calvincchan.com Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada Web: <u>calvincchan.com</u>
Github: <u>github.com/calvincchan</u>
Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/calvincchan</u>



INTRO

For the last decade, my entrepreneur journey taught me to build fast, learn from mistakes, and embrace change based on feedbacks and validation. I have been responsible for designing the architecture of new software, building micro-service based REST-API servers, creating web and mobile clients, managing cloud infrastructure, and implementing deployment pipelines.

EXPERIENCE

Founding Software Engineer - EDU.INK Limited (Hong Kong)

Jun 2019 - Present

Impacts

- Led the development of a real-time collaborative CMS application using React and Supabase to modernize secure information sharing among leadership, nurses, and other contributors of the school learning support team.
- Built a school donation system that accepts public donations, satisfying requirements to integrate with lesser-known UnionPay payment gateway and eTapestry charity software.
- Led the development of all major products, including a student information system, admission and enrolment system, billing and online payment system, library system, school bus tracking system, and parent-teacher communication platform.
- Led the transition from the legacy monolithic PHP Laravel app to a client-server architecture with Node.js + MongoDB backend, Vue.js frontend, and React Native mobile apps. This resulted in dramatic improvements in service responsiveness, development speed, and maintainability.

Responsibilities

- · Collaborate with clients and business team to elicit requirements and design prototypes.
- Researched and evaluated new tech stacks and applied them to product developments.
- Design and implement micro-services and clients quickly to iterate based on feedbacks.
- Coordinate with 2 React Native developers to manage the iOS/Android mobile app development, testing, deployment and release pipelines on both platforms.

Technology

 Node.js, Javascript/Typescript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Jest, Supabase, Docker, Fastify, Restify, Express.js, OpenAPI, Stripe, MasterCard, eTapestry, Active Directory, OneSignal, Vue.js (v2), React.js, Material UI, refine.js, React Native, CircleCI, BitBucket Pipeline, AWS EC2, Docker, AWS S3, Google Cloud Platform, Axure RP, Adobe Illustrator

Founding Software Engineer - GUZZU Limited (Shenzhen, China)

Jun 2016 - Sep 2019

Impacts

- Implemented an expat-focused e-commerce platform featuring a bilingual interface to help English-speaking business owners manage their businesses and serve Chinese customers.
- Built WeChat mini-programs that allow merchants to engage easily with local customers.
- Collaborated with an Android developer to create a proof-of-concept merchant POS terminal.
- Streamlined local event hosting by custom-building a mobile-web event ticket sales platform, including a management backend and a barcode scanning ticket validation app.

Responsibilities

- Directed a team of 2 developers in developing the Node.js API servers, mobile web clients and WeChat mini programs for multiple e-commerce products including: an inventory management system, shopping apps for mobile web, WeChat integration, online payment gateway integration, customizable storefronts, and e-ticket issuance and redemption system.
- Engaged with local expat merchants to strategize new products and features.

Technology

• Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Redis, Vue.js, WeChat Mini Program SDK, Aliyun Cloud

Contract Software Engineer - archiparti.co (Hong Kong)

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

 Built software solutions for architects to simplify the management of their interior design projects, enabling them to focus on their creative process rather than organizing documents and paperwork.

Technology

Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Angular.js, AWS

Founding Software Engineer - giftpass.cn (Shanghai, China)

Mar 2013 - Jun 2015

- As a team in the Chinaccelerator incubator program, I designed and implemented a digital gift voucher platform that streamlines the management and consumption lifecycle for both consumers and merchants.
- Created a merchant app for managing offers, scanning and redeeming gift vouchers.
- Designed pitch decks, visuals and prototypes.
- Rapidly built proof-of-concept projects and MVPs.

Technology

· Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Apple Wallet SDK, Angular.js, WeChat, Aliyun Cloud

UX Designer - Genesix Inc. (Japan)

May 2011 - Jul 2012

- Worked with product managers and iOS engineers on the Jumvo app, a voice based instant messaging tool which received positive user feedbacks and sparked interests in the southeast asian market.
- Contributed to other mobile web marketing projects
- Designed the user experience, interface, and visual elements for iOS and mobile web apps.
- Conducted user interviews and research.

Technology

· Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, jQuery Mobile

Web Designer and Engineer - A.C.O. Inc. (Japan)

Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

- Contributed to building websites for international corporate clients using web design, rapid prototyping, and UI engineering skills with technologies such as Adobe Fireworks and jQuery.
- Developed a Facebook Page and social application for global marketing initiatives that successfully increased brand awareness and user engagement.

Technology

· Adobe Fireworks, Adobe Photoshop, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

InnateDB Software Developer - The University of British Columbia (Canada)

Mar 2007 - Jun 2010

- Designed and implemented the search engine frontend for researchers to easily submit queries and interact with the database content.
- Worked with DB admins and project managers to build the interactive search engine frontend.
- Implemented data visualization and report generation features.

Technology

· Javascript, CSS, jQuery, HTML, PHP, CakePHP

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia — B.Sc., Computer Science

Sep 2000 - May 2003

For more information about me and my recent activities, please visit my personal site: calvincchan.com